lifeway.com 2019-12-15

# Privacy Policy | LifeWay

This is a website of LifeWay Christian Resources or you may have been directed here by one of our Apps. We respect your privacy. We do this by carefully protecting information that you provide to us. Please be aware that we appreciate the trust that you place in us by providing information on this website, and our commitment to you is to use this information with both care and sensitivity. The following discloses what information our websites and Apps (hereinafter "website" or "site") collect and what we do with it.

### Website Privacy

When you connect to this website, we are able to recognize the internet (IP) address of the computer providing you with internet access. Our use of this IP address may be to help diagnose problems with our server or otherwise administer our website. This IP address may also be used to gather broad demographic information. Your IP address is never associated with you as an individual and never provided to another company or organization.

### Other Websites

This website may contain links to other internet sites that are not operated or controlled by LifeWay Christian Resources. We cannot be responsible for the privacy practices or the content of sites that do not belong to LifeWay Christian Resources. We encourage you to read the Privacy Policy of every website you visit.

### Use and Disclosure of Information

We do not collect your name or email address, unless you provide it on a registration form, order form, survey form, or send us an email. Our site's forms may ask or require you to give us contact information (such as your email address), financial information (such as your account or credit card numbers), and demographic information (such as your ZIP code or age). We use this information to provide information, products, or services that you request. For example, financial information is used to bill you for products and services that you order. Any information collected is primarily for internal LifeWay.com use and is not made available to any outside group or organization except other agencies associated with the Southern Baptist Convention or companies working with LifeWay.com for designated purposes.

You have the option to provide personally identifiable and demographic information (such as name, age, gender, ZIP code, church name, denomination, ministry involvement, job position, etc). We encourage you to submit this information so that we can better understand who our users are.

If you provide personally identifiable information to this site, we may combine such information with other actively collected information unless we specify otherwise at the point of collection.   

We also may disclose personally identifiable information you provide via this site to third parties that are not LifeWay Christian Resources affiliates, but only:

  1. to contractors we use to support our business (such as research vendor and technical support), in which case we will require such third parties to agree to treat it in accordance with this Privacy Policy and use it for the same purposes;
  2. to respond to law enforcement requests or where required by applicable laws, court orders, or government regulations.

The collection, use, and disclosure of information contemplated in this Privacy Policy may involve a transfer of the information to jurisdictions located outside your country of residence that may not have equivalent laws and rules regarding personally identifiable information. By giving this information, you are giving your consent for such transfers and disclosures in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Online Tracking

Our website does not currently respond to web browser "Do Not Track" signals or other similar mechanisms. Also, as described in the "Use and disclosure of information" section above, we may use third-party vendors or software which could track your activities across third-party web sites or online services to help us enhance your experience on our site. 

### Children's Privacy

LifeWay Christian Resources takes children's privacy seriously and maintains compliance with the rules defined by the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). We do not seek to collect individually identifiable information for children under 13 years of age.

If LifeWay Christian Resources learns that a child under the age of 13 has submitted personally identifiable information online, in contravention of these measures, LifeWay Christian Resources will take all reasonable measures to delete such information from its databases and to not use such information for any purpose (except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others as required by law).

### Access, Correction, and Update

To keep personally identifiable information that you provide via this site accurate, current, and complete, please update your information on file with LifeWay Christian Resources by filling out the appropriate forms on the website with your new contact and personally identifiable information.

### Data Security

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it, from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. You should keep in mind that no internet transmission is ever completely secure or error-free. In particular, email sent to or from this site may not be secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact us.

### Spam

This is an opt-in email program. You will only receive emails from LifeWay Christian Resources based on the information you supply us. If you no longer want to receive these email communications, you must change your communication preference when you next update your profile.

### Surveys

When you pre-qualify for a survey, LifeWay Christian Resources may, from time to time, invite you to participate in online surveys. The information requested in these surveys may include, but is not limited to, your opinions, beliefs, insights, ideas, activities, experience, purchase history, and purchase intent regarding products, events, and services. The information collected by these surveys is used to research market trends, church trends, ministry growth, congregation, and community needs. Your inputs will impact LifeWay Christian Resources' published research, help us to improve customer experience, shape new product development, equip church ministry effectiveness, and enhance individuals' spiritual growth and experience.

### Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

We use persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your internet browser's "help" file. More information about cookie technology can be found on the Microsoft® website at: www.microsoft.com/info/cookies.mspx.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site may be limited. As some of our promotions or surveys may be targeted towards responses to a particular marketing program, if the persistent cookie for that program is not present due to visitor deletion, you may not be invited to participate in the corresponding survey or promotion.

We participate in the Adobe Marketing Cloud Device Co-op to understand how you use our website and apps across different devices you use, in order to deliver advertising based on your interests. You can learn more about how Adobe does this, and how to opt-out, at <https://cross-device-privacy.adobe.com/>.  

### Non-Electronic Communications

In addition, we occasionally may employ other companies to perform fulfillment mailings on our behalf. They may have access to the personal information needed to fulfill their functions, but may not use it for any other purposes.

### Data Security

This site has security measures (including online and off-line physical, electronic and managerial safeguards) in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. As with any transmission over the internet, however, there is always some element of risk involved in sending personal information online. Your email address, password, and cookie will be required to redeem Rewards, update your personal information (name, email address, etc.), and update your Member profile data. Remember to keep your password private and secure. You should not share this information with anyone. If you have any questions about the security at our website, you can contact us.

### Our Opt-Out Policy

If you no longer wish to participate in our surveys and email newsletters, please be sure to scroll down to the bottom of the email you receive and click on the opt-out link provided, which will remove your record from our database. You will then receive no further marketing communications from us. If you do not opt out using the link at the bottom of our first email you receive (or any emails thereafter), you will continue to receive surveys and email newsletters until you choose to click on the opt-out link that will be provided in each email you receive from us.

### Changes in the Privacy Promise

We reserve the right to modify and update this Privacy Policy at any time by posting an amended version of the statement on the LifeWay Christian Resources website. Please refer to this policy regularly. If at any time we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you either on the panel home page of our website or via email.

### How to Contact Us

LifeWay Christian Resources is firmly committed to protecting your privacy. Because protecting your privacy is important to us, you may always submit concerns regarding our Privacy Policy on the contact us page. LifeWay Christian Resources will attempt to respond to all reasonable concerns and inquiries expeditiously.

### Mailing Address

LifeWay Christian Resources  
Attention: Privacy Policy   
One LifeWay Plaza  
Nashville, TN 37234-0140, USA
